Guide to the Lillian Baker Griggs Papers, 1930-1949
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Lillian Baker Griggs papers 1930-1949
University Archives, Duke University
Griggs, Lillian Baker, 1876-1955.
1.5 Linear Feet 1,500 Items
Papers of Lillian Baker Griggs, Librarian of the Duke University Woman's College Library, 1930 to 1949.
Contains primarily correspondence, library planning records, budget files, and other materials related to the operation of the Woman's College Library. The correspondence covers activities of the North Carolina Library, the American Library Association, library legislation and education, as well as the Woman's College Library. Also includes a 60 page typed memoir written by Griggs, ca. 1940
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Lillian Baker Griggs Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1971-1972, 1976, 1983.
Biographical Note
Lillian Baker Griggs was born in Anderson, South Carolina in 1867 to William F. and Cora D. Baker. She graduated from Agnes Scott College in 1895 and married Alfred Flourny Griggs in 1897. After her husband's death in 1908, she entered the Carnegie Library School in Atlanta and received her certificate in 1911. From 1911 to 1923 she was Librarian for the Durham Public Library and from 1924 until 1930 served as Director of the North Carolina Library Commission. In 1930 she became the first Librarian of the Duke University Woman's College Library. Committed to undergraduate library service, it was her goal "to have every girl on campus come into the library at least one time." (Box 2 correspondence, Dec. 14, 1937).
Griggs actively served in a number of professional organizations, including the League of Library Commissions (President, 1929-1930), the North Carolina Library Association (President, 1917-1918, 1931-1932), the Southeastern Library Association, the North Carolina Literary and Historical Association, the North Carolina Folklore Society, and the League of Women Voters.
Collection Overview
Primarily correspondence, library planning, budget files, and other materials related to the operation of the Woman's College Library of Duke University. The correspondence covers activities of the North Carolina Library, the American Library Association, library legislation and education, as well as the Woman's College Library. Box 3 includes a 60 page typed memoir written by Lillian Baker Griggs, ca. 1940
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
American Library Association.
Duke University. Woman’s College Library.
Griggs, Lillian Baker, 1976-1955.
North Carolina Library Association.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 3 Boxes
  - Correspondence, 1930 - May 1933 (6 folders) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1940 (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 3)
  - Woman's College Library planning, 1930-1934
  - Woman's College Library financial and collection reports, 1931-1943
  - Woman's College Library budget, 1935-1947 (7 folders)
  - Woman's College Library Committee, 1937-1949
  - Woman's Club of Durham, 1933-1934
  - Memoirs of Mrs. Alfred (Lillian B.) Griggs, 1876-1955; written 1940